# TIGER O'BRIEN

Junior Developer

+61 421 346 032

<u>tiger-obrien.netlify.app/</u>

linkedin.com/in/tiger-obrien/

Melbourne VIC 3000

github.com/tigerob

# **Education & Qualifications**

2022 **Web-Development Bootcamp** Coder Academy

2016 Admission to legal practice (Victoria & Commonwealth)

2015 Juris Doctor

University of Melbourne

- 94th percentile LSAT
- Global Mobility U21 Scholarship recipient

2012 **Bachelor of Commerce** University of Melbourne

2008 VCE

• 97.05 ENTER

# **Key skills**

- Web-app development
- · Back-end development
- Software testing
- Productive collaboration across different functions and levels
- Project management
- Ownership of outcomes
- Large capacity and desire to learn

### **Tech skills**

- Languages: JavaScript, Ruby, HTML, CSS, Markdown
- Frameworks & Libraries: ReactJS, Rails
- DBMSs: PostgreSQL
- Tools: Terminal, Git, VS Code, Trello, GitHub, Balsamiq Wireframes

#### **Interests**













#### Referees

Available upon request

# **Summary**

Emerging software developer fostering skills in all phases of the development life cycle: requirements analysis, design, development, testing, documentation and maintenance. Experienced project manager, effective communicator and productive collaborator. Significant capacity and desire to continue growing competencies through commercial projects.

# **Key projects**

### Rails Marketplace App - Fridges For All

- A two-sided marketplace on which users can buy and sell second-hand refrigerators
- Features include: user sign up and log in, user authentication, create/view/edit/delete listing, upload image (with Amazon S3), purchase listing (with Stripe)
- Tech: Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL, SCSS, Bootstrap, Heroku, Amazon S3, Stripe, Ultrahook

### Ruby Terminal App - 21 Books You've Been Meaning To Read

- A terminal app that gives users various interactive ways to choose from Penguin Random House's 'The 21 Books You've Been Meaning To Read'
- Features include choosing by: genre, undertaking a quiz, and random selection

#### **HTML & CSS Website - Portfolio**

• A portfolio showcasing me as an emerging software developer and providing users with links to my relevant pages and ways to contact me, including by contact form

# **Professional Experience**

#### **Anindilyakwa Land Council**

Feb 2018 - Sep 2019

#### Legal, Strategy & Operations Manager

- One of the four Northern Territory Aboriginal Land Councils medium-sized statutory corporation advancing Aboriginal interests for part of East Arnhem Land.
- Developed and implemented strategies to achieve economic, infrastructure and community outcomes for 1,616 Aboriginal Traditional Owners, including by deploying c. \$86m p.a. Reported to CEO and Board.
- Identified unmet Aboriginal Traditional Owner needs and collaborated with stakeholders to test and communicate solutions. These stakeholders included commercial partners, Commonwealth Government, NT Government, GEMCO (world's largest manganese ore producer), NGOs and trusts.
- Managed project execution, negotiations and legal matters.

#### **Baker McKenzie**

Mar 2016 - Feb 2018

# **Associate (Corporate Markets)**

- Mergers-and-acquisitions (M&A) and equity-capital-markets lawyer at one of the world's largest law firms, acting in transactions ranging from \$5m to \$15b in value.
- Member of the #1-ranked M&A team in AUS/NZ for deal value.
- Managed M&A deals and advised clients on key deal issues across sectors including technology, financial services, consumer goods, manufacturing, infrastructure, energy, healthcare, telecommunications and education.

# **Volunteer Experience**

The NCOBF Foundation Mar 2017 – Present

#### **Advisory Committee Member**

- Advisory Committee Member for one of Australia's 50 biggest private philanthropic givers.
- Engage with donees, assess proposed projects, recommend projects to Foundation Board and evaluate ongoing projects.

#### Women's Legal Service Victoria

May 2016 - Feb 2018

#### Lawyer

- Assisted women and children who were victims of domestic violence with Victorian Victims of Crime Assistance Tribunal claims.
- Interviewed clients, obtained supporting evidence, and prepared and progressed claims.

### Victorian Aboriginal Legal Service

Dec 2012 - May 2014

#### **Legal Volunteer**

• Worked with clients, lawyers, courts, mediators and police. Prepared for court proceedings and conducted legal and policy research.

# **Key Achievements**

#### **Community Support Program** (Anindilyakwa Land Council, 2018)

• Led a cross-functional team to develop and communicate to Aboriginal Traditional Owners a program that delivered \$4.7m p.a. in services to 1,616 community members (including for essential goods and services, aged and medical care, education, welfare and energy) and operated with 22 employees.

#### Mining joint venture (Anindilyakwa Land Council, 2018)

• Collaborated on the establishment of an <u>Aboriginal-Chinese mining JV</u> and \$5m purchase of mining tenement interests, enabling Aboriginal Traditional Owners to actively participate in Groote Archipelago mining for the first time and increase the scale of benefit they derive from their resources.

#### GA Housing Corporation (Anindilyakwa Land Council, 2018)

Established and marketed to Aboriginal Traditional Owners this corporation to fulfil housing-related service needs for 322 houses.

#### Groote Archipelago Local Decision-Making Agreement (Anindilyakwa Land Council, 2018 and 2019)

• Identified Aboriginal Traditional Owner needs and, consequently, successfully negotiated and commenced implementation of a multi-million-dollar agreement with the NT Government to grow local operations in the areas of commerce, housing, law and justice, education, health, local governance and renewable power.

### Future Groote Strategy (Anindilyakwa Land Council, 2019)

• Identified the relevant priorities of corporations and Aboriginal Traditional Owners and collaborated with consultants Social Ventures Australia to develop a long-term strategy to improve economic and social operations for the Groote Archipelago. Brought together 25 stakeholders to commence implementation of the strategy.

# Cross-border renewable energy project acquisition (Baker McKenzie 2017)

• Led the six-week completion of a \$5.5m renewable energy project acquisition, including by collaborating with the vendor company, the vendor company's counsel, the purchasing company and internal work streams across multiple functions and levels.

# Barunga Agreement (Anindilyakwa Land Council, 2018)

• One of 18 members of the multi-party Working Group for Treaty to settle an agreement for Northern Territory Aboriginal treaty.

### **Aboriginal control of land** (Anindilyakwa Land Council, 2019)

• Negotiated a change to the Groote Archipelago head lease to allow transfer from Commonwealth to Aboriginal control.